<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.2.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://www.recherche-reproductible.fr//feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://www.recherche-reproductible.fr//" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2024-02-13T19:33:11+00:00</updated><id>https://www.recherche-reproductible.fr//feed.xml</id><title type="html">Recherche Reproductible</title><subtitle>Un réseau national de chercheurs pour la promotion de la recherche reproductible.</subtitle><author><name>Recherche Reproductible</name></author><entry><title type="html">Journées du réseau français de recherche reproductible 2024</title><link href="https://www.recherche-reproductible.fr//event/2024/03/26/jrfrr-2024.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Journées du réseau français de recherche reproductible 2024" /><published>2024-03-26T12:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-03-26T12:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.recherche-reproductible.fr//event/2024/03/26/jrfrr-2024</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.recherche-reproductible.fr//event/2024/03/26/jrfrr-2024.html"><![CDATA[<p>Les inscriptions aux journées du réseau recherche reproductible qui auront lieu du <strong>26 au 28 Mars 2024 à Grenoble</strong> sont ouvertes !</p>

<p><a href="https://jrfrr-2024.sciencesconf.org/registration">Inscriptions</a></p>

<p>Il s’agit d’un moment important pour la consolidation du réseau et le dynamisme des collaborations émergentes. Ce colloque fait suite aux <a href="https://www.recherche-reproductible.fr/rr-days/">journées organisées en mars</a> 2023 à l’Institut Pasteur.</p>

<p>Le <a href="https://jrfrr-2024.sciencesconf.org/resource/page/id/1">programme</a> de ces journées 2024 met l’accent sur le retours d’expériences de deux réseaux en Europe, la reproductibilité expérimentale dans différentes disciplines et sur les actions de formation. Les différentes sessions ne seront certainement pas représentatives de toute la diversité des pratiques mais le but des ces journées (et des discusions que l’on espère fructueuses) est de partager et faire découvrir nos différentes problématiques, définitions et mises en pratique.</p>

<p>Un des enjeux de ce colloque est également de réfléchir à la définition et à la gouvernance de ce réseau qui nous permette un échange d’informations sur les formations, les ateliers, les conférences et de pouvoir péréniser l’organisation de ces journées.</p>

<p>N’hésitez pas à diffuser cette information dans vos réseaux !</p>]]></content><author><name>Recherche Reproductible</name></author><category term="event" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Les inscriptions aux journées du réseau recherche reproductible qui auront lieu du 26 au 28 Mars 2024 à Grenoble sont ouvertes !]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">52e Forum Orap : Reproductibilité et HPC</title><link href="https://www.recherche-reproductible.fr//news/2024/03/15/Forum_Orap_Reproductibilit%C3%A9_HPC.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="52e Forum Orap : Reproductibilité et HPC" /><published>2024-03-15T13:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-03-15T13:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.recherche-reproductible.fr//news/2024/03/15/Forum_Orap_Reproductibilit%C3%A9_HPC</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.recherche-reproductible.fr//news/2024/03/15/Forum_Orap_Reproductibilit%C3%A9_HPC.html"><![CDATA[<p>ORAP organise deux fois par an un “Forum” destiné à permettre aux acteurs du calcul de haute performance de se rencontrer et de disposer d’un espace de “veille technologique” sur ce domaine.</p>

<p>Le prochain Forum ORAP aura lieu vendredi 15 mars prochain de 9h à 17h au Siège du CNRS, 3 rue Michel-Ange, Paris 16e.</p>

<p>Le thème de ce Forum est : « Reproductibilité et HPC ».</p>

<p>Le programme est disponible ici et l’inscription est ouverte https://orap52.sciencesconf.org</p>

<p>La reproductibilité est un sujet important pour les communautés scientifiques. Le calcul haute performance présente des spécificités qui interrogent sur la notion de reproductibilité. L’objectif de la journée est de faire le point sur ces questions, en identifiant les problématiques et en s’appuyant sur des retours d’expérience de différentes communautés scientifiques.</p>]]></content><author><name>Recherche Reproductible</name></author><category term="news" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[ORAP organise deux fois par an un “Forum” destiné à permettre aux acteurs du calcul de haute performance de se rencontrer et de disposer d’un espace de “veille technologique” sur ce domaine.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Webinaire : IPOL journal and its approach to open science</title><link href="https://www.recherche-reproductible.fr//news/2024/02/08/IPOL-journal-open-science.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Webinaire : IPOL journal and its approach to open science" /><published>2024-02-08T13:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-02-08T13:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.recherche-reproductible.fr//news/2024/02/08/IPOL-journal-open-science</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.recherche-reproductible.fr//news/2024/02/08/IPOL-journal-open-science.html"><![CDATA[<p>David Donoho and many others pointed out in 2009 what is known nowadays as the reproducibility crisis in scientific research. This lack of credibility has consequences in the quality and credibility of research results. The modest contribution of Centre Borelli to mitigate this problem is the IPOL journal, started in 2009. This open-science journal publishes reproducible research on mathematical algorithms where each article comes with a open-source implementation, at least reviewed by two referees. Each article comes along with an online demo that allows any user to test the algorithm with their own data, as well as having access to a large archive of previously performed experiences.</p>

<p>In this short talk I will present the IPOL journal, how it is indexed as a publisher, how the submitted research (paper, software, and data) is evaluated, the impact of IPOL publications. I will finally draw some personal conclusions on why we should all perform reproducible research, but still it is hard to convince everybody to follow this path.</p>

<p>Ce webinaire sera animé par <strong>Miguel Colom-Barco</strong>, enseignant chercheur à l’ENS Paris Saclay.</p>

<p>Les informations de connexion (zoom) seront diffusés sur le site web :
https://reproducibility.gricad-pages.univ-grenoble-alpes.fr/web/</p>]]></content><author><name>Recherche Reproductible</name></author><category term="news" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[David Donoho and many others pointed out in 2009 what is known nowadays as the reproducibility crisis in scientific research. This lack of credibility has consequences in the quality and credibility of research results. The modest contribution of Centre Borelli to mitigate this problem is the IPOL journal, started in 2009. This open-science journal publishes reproducible research on mathematical algorithms where each article comes with a open-source implementation, at least reviewed by two referees. Each article comes along with an online demo that allows any user to test the algorithm with their own data, as well as having access to a large archive of previously performed experiences.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Chargé.e de projet pour le réseau français de la recherche reproductible</title><link href="https://www.recherche-reproductible.fr//news/2024/01/15/chargee_projet.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Chargé.e de projet pour le réseau français de la recherche reproductible" /><published>2024-01-15T11:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-01-15T11:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.recherche-reproductible.fr//news/2024/01/15/chargee_projet</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.recherche-reproductible.fr//news/2024/01/15/chargee_projet.html"><![CDATA[<p>Bonjour à toutes et tous,</p>

<p>Le réseau français de la recherche reproductible cherche un.e chargé.e de projet en CDD de 18 mois renouvelable, niveau doctorat.</p>

<p>Ce réseau a trois principaux objectifs :</p>

<ol>
  <li>former les membres et supporter la mise en place d’actions visant à améliorer la reproductibilité,</li>
  <li>former un réseau de réseaux pour aligner et promouvoir les stratégies et les politiques en faveur de la recherche reproductible aux niveaux national et international, et</li>
  <li>fournir des supports éducatifs et de formation ainsi que des formateurs à la communauté.</li>
</ol>

<p>Afin d’aider à la croissance de ce réseau et à l’implémentation de ses objectifs, nous recherchons un.e chargé.e de projet, dont la mission principale sera d’approfondir la structuration, d’animer et de coordonner les différentes activité du réseau, notamment avec les autres structures nationales (réseaux, GDR, labos) et européennes (EOSC, réseaux européens de la recherche reproductible, projets européens).</p>

<p>Pour plus d’informations et pour candidater, veuiller vous rendre sur la page <a href="https://recrutement.inria.fr/public/classic/fr/offres/2024-07107">suivante</a>.</p>

<p>Contact :</p>

<p>Comité de pilotage du réseau français de la recherche reproductible: recherche-reproductible-copil@groupes.renater.fr</p>]]></content><author><name>Recherche Reproductible</name></author><category term="news" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Bonjour à toutes et tous,]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The role of replication in scientific controversies</title><link href="https://www.recherche-reproductible.fr//event/2023/11/09/NanoBubble.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The role of replication in scientific controversies" /><published>2023-11-09T08:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-11-09T08:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.recherche-reproductible.fr//event/2023/11/09/NanoBubble</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.recherche-reproductible.fr//event/2023/11/09/NanoBubble.html"><![CDATA[<p>This <a href="https://nanobubbles.hypotheses.org/2139">3-day symposium</a> is aimed at stimulating informal discussions on replications and unresolved questions about nanoparticles inside cells. We will combine talks of scientists who have engaged in research in nanobiology namely on nanoparticle entry into the cell (described below), with talks by researchers who have studied replications from a historical, philosophical, sociological, or anthropological perspective. Our goal is to create a space for an interdisciplinary exchange about replications of results whose credibility has been questioned.</p>

<p>More information at https://nanobubbles.hypotheses.org/2139</p>]]></content><author><name>Recherche Reproductible</name></author><category term="event" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[This 3-day symposium is aimed at stimulating informal discussions on replications and unresolved questions about nanoparticles inside cells. We will combine talks of scientists who have engaged in research in nanobiology namely on nanoparticle entry into the cell (described below), with talks by researchers who have studied replications from a historical, philosophical, sociological, or anthropological perspective. Our goal is to create a space for an interdisciplinary exchange about replications of results whose credibility has been questioned.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Workshop on Reproducible Software Environments for Research and High-Performance Computing</title><link href="https://www.recherche-reproductible.fr//event/2023/11/08/Reproducible-Software-Environments.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Workshop on Reproducible Software Environments for Research and High-Performance Computing" /><published>2023-11-08T12:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-11-08T12:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.recherche-reproductible.fr//event/2023/11/08/Reproducible-Software-Environments</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.recherche-reproductible.fr//event/2023/11/08/Reproducible-Software-Environments.html"><![CDATA[<p>The first <a href="https://hpc.guix.info/events/2023/workshop/">Workshop on Reproducible Software Environments for Research
and High-Performance Computing
(HPC)</a> will take place in
Montpellier, France, 8–10 November 2023.</p>

<p>The <a href="https://hpc.guix.info/events/2023/workshop/program">program</a>
features talks by scientists, engineers, and system administrators from
different backgrounds who will share their experience with
<a href="https://hpc.guix.info">GNU Guix</a>, a tool for reproducible software
deployment.  It also includes tutorials on GitLab, Guix, and other tools
that support scientific workflows—from bioinfo analyses to HPC and
source code archival.</p>

<p>The workshop aims to be a hub for scientists and practitioners,
newcomers and experts.</p>]]></content><author><name>Recherche Reproductible</name></author><category term="event" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[The first Workshop on Reproducible Software Environments for Research and High-Performance Computing (HPC) will take place in Montpellier, France, 8–10 November 2023.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Réplicabilité/reproductibilité de la recherche : enjeux et propositions</title><link href="https://www.recherche-reproductible.fr//past-event/2023/09/08/CNRS-Colloque-event.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Réplicabilité/reproductibilité de la recherche : enjeux et propositions" /><published>2023-09-08T08:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-09-08T08:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.recherche-reproductible.fr//past-event/2023/09/08/CNRS-Colloque-event</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.recherche-reproductible.fr//past-event/2023/09/08/CNRS-Colloque-event.html"><![CDATA[<p>La recherche scientifique se voit constamment confrontée à des défis concernant ce qui est communément appelé la réplicabilité de ses résultats. La définition de ce concept paraît simple puisqu’il s’agit, pour un observateur extérieur, de s’assurer qu’une analyse et ses résultats mobilisant des données et leur traitement puissent être reproduits parfaitement, à l’identique. La notion de réplicabilité se trouve sans aucun doute au cœur du vaste mouvement mondial de science ouverte, au sein duquel s’inscrit la récente feuille de route du CNRS en la matière. Mais si sa définition peut apparaître triviale, il n’en reste pas moins que son application pratique pose des problèmes pertinents, qui engagent notre réflexion et appellent des solutions innovantes.</p>

<p>Les deux objectifs principaux de <a href="https://miti.cnrs.fr/evenement-scientifique/colloque-replicabilite-reproductibilite-recherche/">cette journée</a> sont de :</p>

<ul>
  <li>
    <p>Confronter les regards et pratiques des disciplines sur le sujet de la réplicabilité/reproductibilité ; développer une réflexion interdisciplinaire sur le sens et les limites de ces deux concepts, sur les éléments communs ou au contraire distants selon les disciplines.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Dégager des éléments pouvant irriguer la politique scientifique du CNRS et le placer dans un rôle dynamique d’organisme leader sur le sujet.</p>
  </li>
</ul>

<p>Plus d’information sur: https://miti.cnrs.fr/evenement-scientifique/colloque-replicabilite-reproductibilite-recherche/</p>]]></content><author><name>Recherche Reproductible</name></author><category term="past-event" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[La recherche scientifique se voit constamment confrontée à des défis concernant ce qui est communément appelé la réplicabilité de ses résultats. La définition de ce concept paraît simple puisqu’il s’agit, pour un observateur extérieur, de s’assurer qu’une analyse et ses résultats mobilisant des données et leur traitement puissent être reproduits parfaitement, à l’identique. La notion de réplicabilité se trouve sans aucun doute au cœur du vaste mouvement mondial de science ouverte, au sein duquel s’inscrit la récente feuille de route du CNRS en la matière. Mais si sa définition peut apparaître triviale, il n’en reste pas moins que son application pratique pose des problèmes pertinents, qui engagent notre réflexion et appellent des solutions innovantes.]]></summary></entry><entry xml:lang="english"><title type="html">The Replication Crisis is Less of a “Crisis” in the Lakatosian Approach than it is in the Popperian and Naïve Methodological Falsificationism Approaches</title><link href="https://www.recherche-reproductible.fr//publication/2023/08/23/replication-crisis.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Replication Crisis is Less of a “Crisis” in the Lakatosian Approach than it is in the Popperian and Naïve Methodological Falsificationism Approaches" /><published>2023-08-23T07:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-08-23T07:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.recherche-reproductible.fr//publication/2023/08/23/replication-crisis</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.recherche-reproductible.fr//publication/2023/08/23/replication-crisis.html"><![CDATA[<p>Popper’s (1983, 2002) philosophy of science has enjoyed something of a renaissance in the wake of the replication crisis, offering a philosophical basis for the ensuing science reform movement. However, adherence to Popper’s approach may also be at least partly responsible for the sense of “crisis” that has developed following multiple unexpected replication failures. In this article, I contrast Popper’s approach with Lakatos’ (1978) approach and a related approach called naïve methodological falsificationism (NMF; Lakatos, 1978). The Popperian approach is powerful because it is based on logical refutation, but its theories are noncausal and, therefore, lacking in scientific value. In contrast, the Lakatosian approach tests causal theories, but it concedes that these theories are not logically refutable. Finally, the NMF approach subjects Lakatosian causal theories to Popperian logical refutations. However, its approach of temporarily accepting a ceteris paribus clause during theory testing may be viewed as scientifically inappropriate, epistemically inconsistent, and “completely redundant” (Lakatos, 1978, p. 40). I conclude that a replication “crisis” makes the most sense in the context of the Popperian and NMF approaches because it is only in these two approaches that replication failures represent logical refutations of theories. In contrast, replication failures are less problematic in the Lakatosian approach because they do not logically refute theories. Indeed, in the Lakatosian approach, replication failures can be legitimately ignored or used to motivate theory development.</p>

<p><a href="https://osf.io/preprints/metaarxiv/2dz9s/"><span id="Rubin2023"><span style="font-variant: small-caps">Rubin, M.</span> 2023. The replication crisis is less of a “crisis” in the Lakatosian approach than it is in the Popperian and naïve methodological falsificationism approaches. .</span></a></p>]]></content><author><name>Recherche Reproductible</name></author><category term="publication" /><category term="metascience" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Popper’s (1983, 2002) philosophy of science has enjoyed something of a renaissance in the wake of the replication crisis, offering a philosophical basis for the ensuing science reform movement. However, adherence to Popper’s approach may also be at least partly responsible for the sense of “crisis” that has developed following multiple unexpected replication failures. In this article, I contrast Popper’s approach with Lakatos’ (1978) approach and a related approach called naïve methodological falsificationism (NMF; Lakatos, 1978). The Popperian approach is powerful because it is based on logical refutation, but its theories are noncausal and, therefore, lacking in scientific value. In contrast, the Lakatosian approach tests causal theories, but it concedes that these theories are not logically refutable. Finally, the NMF approach subjects Lakatosian causal theories to Popperian logical refutations. However, its approach of temporarily accepting a ceteris paribus clause during theory testing may be viewed as scientifically inappropriate, epistemically inconsistent, and “completely redundant” (Lakatos, 1978, p. 40). I conclude that a replication “crisis” makes the most sense in the context of the Popperian and NMF approaches because it is only in these two approaches that replication failures represent logical refutations of theories. In contrast, replication failures are less problematic in the Lakatosian approach because they do not logically refute theories. Indeed, in the Lakatosian approach, replication failures can be legitimately ignored or used to motivate theory development.]]></summary></entry><entry xml:lang="english"><title type="html">A reproducible and generalizable software workflow for analysis of large-scale neuroimaging data collections using BIDS Apps</title><link href="https://www.recherche-reproductible.fr//publication/2023/08/18/repro-BIDS.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A reproducible and generalizable software workflow for analysis of large-scale neuroimaging data collections using BIDS Apps" /><published>2023-08-18T07:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-08-18T07:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.recherche-reproductible.fr//publication/2023/08/18/repro-BIDS</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.recherche-reproductible.fr//publication/2023/08/18/repro-BIDS.html"><![CDATA[<p>Neuroimaging research faces a crisis of reproducibility. With massive sample sizes and greater data complexity, this problem becomes more acute. Software that operates on imaging data defined using the Brain Imaging Data Structure (BIDS) – BIDS Apps – have provided a substantial advance. However, even using BIDS Apps, a full audit trail of data processing is a necessary prerequisite for fully reproducible research. Obtaining a faithful record of the audit trail is challenging – especially for large datasets. Recently, the FAIRly big framework was introduced as a way to facilitate reproducible processing of large-scale data by leveraging DataLad – a version control system for data management. However, the current implementation of this framework was more of a proof of concept, and could not be immediately reused by other investigators for different use cases. Here we introduce the BIDS App Bootstrap (BABS), a user-friendly and generalizable Python package for reproducible image processing at scale. BABS facilitates the reproducible application of BIDS Apps to large-scale datasets. Leveraging DataLad and the FAIRly big framework, BABS tracks the full audit trail of data processing in a scalable way by automatically preparing all scripts necessary for data processing and version tracking on high performance computing (HPC) systems. Currently, BABS supports jobs submissions and audits on Sun Grid Engine (SGE) and Slurm HPCs with a parsimonious set of programs. To demonstrate its scalability, we applied BABS to data from the Healthy Brain Network (HBN; n=2,565). Taken together, BABS allows reproducible and scalable image processing and is broadly extensible via an open-source development model.</p>

<p><a href="https://www.biorxiv.org/content/10.1101/2023.08.16.552472v1?rss=1"><span id="Zhao2023"><span style="font-variant: small-caps">Zhao, C., Jarecka, D., Covitz, S., et al.</span> 2023. A reproducible and generalizable software workflow for analysis of large-scale neuroimaging data collections using BIDS Apps. .</span></a></p>]]></content><author><name>Recherche Reproductible</name></author><category term="publication" /><category term="computational" /><category term="science" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Neuroimaging research faces a crisis of reproducibility. With massive sample sizes and greater data complexity, this problem becomes more acute. Software that operates on imaging data defined using the Brain Imaging Data Structure (BIDS) – BIDS Apps – have provided a substantial advance. However, even using BIDS Apps, a full audit trail of data processing is a necessary prerequisite for fully reproducible research. Obtaining a faithful record of the audit trail is challenging – especially for large datasets. Recently, the FAIRly big framework was introduced as a way to facilitate reproducible processing of large-scale data by leveraging DataLad – a version control system for data management. However, the current implementation of this framework was more of a proof of concept, and could not be immediately reused by other investigators for different use cases. Here we introduce the BIDS App Bootstrap (BABS), a user-friendly and generalizable Python package for reproducible image processing at scale. BABS facilitates the reproducible application of BIDS Apps to large-scale datasets. Leveraging DataLad and the FAIRly big framework, BABS tracks the full audit trail of data processing in a scalable way by automatically preparing all scripts necessary for data processing and version tracking on high performance computing (HPC) systems. Currently, BABS supports jobs submissions and audits on Sun Grid Engine (SGE) and Slurm HPCs with a parsimonious set of programs. To demonstrate its scalability, we applied BABS to data from the Healthy Brain Network (HBN; n=2,565). Taken together, BABS allows reproducible and scalable image processing and is broadly extensible via an open-source development model.]]></summary></entry><entry xml:lang="english"><title type="html">Reprohackathons: promoting reproducibility in bioinformatics through training</title><link href="https://www.recherche-reproductible.fr//publication/2023/06/30/reprohackathons.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Reprohackathons: promoting reproducibility in bioinformatics through training" /><published>2023-06-30T09:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-06-30T09:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.recherche-reproductible.fr//publication/2023/06/30/reprohackathons</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.recherche-reproductible.fr//publication/2023/06/30/reprohackathons.html"><![CDATA[<p>The reproducibility crisis has highlighted the importance of improving the way bioinformatics data analyses are implemented, executed, and shared. To address this, various tools such as content versioning systems, workflow management systems, and software environment management systems have been developed. While these tools are becoming more widely used, there is still much work to be done to increase their adoption. The most effective way to ensure reproducibility becomes a standard part of most bioinformatics data analysis projects is to integrate it into the curriculum of bioinformatics Master’s programs.</p>

<p><a href="https://doi.org/10.1093/bioinformatics/btad227">Reprohackathons: promoting reproducibility in bioinformatics through training</a></p>

<p>Thomas Cokelaer, Sarah Cohen-Boulakia, Frédéric Lemoine — June 30, 2023</p>]]></content><author><name>Recherche Reproductible</name></author><category term="publication" /><category term="science" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[The reproducibility crisis has highlighted the importance of improving the way bioinformatics data analyses are implemented, executed, and shared. To address this, various tools such as content versioning systems, workflow management systems, and software environment management systems have been developed. While these tools are becoming more widely used, there is still much work to be done to increase their adoption. The most effective way to ensure reproducibility becomes a standard part of most bioinformatics data analysis projects is to integrate it into the curriculum of bioinformatics Master’s programs.]]></summary></entry></feed>